

### DR. THINAKARAN M SELVARAJAH

840321-07-5305
46, JLN LANCANG 1, TMN SRI BAHTERA, CHERAS, 56100
KUALA LUMPUR, MALAYSIA
+6012-2094360
thinakaranmd@yahoo.com
Malaysian Medical Council 49898

2015 - 2018

### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

Enthusiastic doctor with a broad mind and passion to contribute to the healthcare industry and society. Looking forward to make best of given opportunities and serve with my experience, knowledge and skills for better growth and reputation of the nation.

EDUCATION	
Doctor of Medicine (MD) Pirogov Russian National Research Medical University (RNRMU), Moscow	2002 - 2008
Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Jalan Cochrane, Kuala Lumpur Secondary Schooling	1997 – 2001

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Assistant Director of Hospital
Women and Children Hospital
Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

# Medical Officer Anesthesiology & Critical Care Hospital Kuala Lumpur

Hospital Kuala Lumpur Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Learning from the experts in each subspecialty nurtured my knowledge. I was able develop my skills further in handling various situations and patients. Being in Anesthesia all this years has taught me to plan for every occasion and to be prepared for any circumstances while knowing my limits.

Communication is another skill that I have picked up along the way in dealing with patients and family to alleviate their anxiety as well as on how to break the bad news. Leadership, execution and team play are among other important skills that helped build my character thus far.

# Medical Officer Anesthesiology & Critical Care

2015

Hospital Ampang Ampang, Selangor

A short transit while awaiting for my placement in Hospital Kuala Lumpur. Being the hematology center, it gave me a new perspective in management of a different group of patients requiring surgical interventions and critical care in the ICU. A memorable 4 months.

#### **Medical Officer Anesthesiology & Critical Care**

2011 - 2015

Hospital Sultan Ismail (HSI) Johor Bahru, Malaysia

Began working in the department of Anesthesiology right after completing my horsemanship. Working in this department thought me valuable skills; the need to be on our feet, being meticulous to details, quick thinking and to decipher problems. Dealt with ill and terminally ill patients requiring intensive care as well as chronic pain management.

A part from regular schedules, I was part of the Transplant and Organ Procurement (TOP) Team in HSI since 2013. Rather active in nurturing the locals and promoting the benefits of being a pledger. I was involved in the clinical teaching of junior medical officers, house officers and medical students when they are attached to the department which is a great joy to me.

Eager to gain more depth into Anesthesia, I applied to be transferred to Hospital Kuala Lumpur where it caters varied portfolio of cases and subspecialties such as Neurosurgery, Pediatric and Neonatal Surgery, Urology and Cardiac Surgeries just to name a few.

**House Officer** 2008 - 2010

Hospital Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia (HUKM) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Rotation in six specialties – Internal Medicine, Orthopedics, Obstetrics and Gynecology, Surgery, Pediatrics and Anesthesiology during my 2 years in HUKM. Anesthesiology and Critical Care was my final posting during the 2 years training and this specialty enticed me the most. This specialty has so much to offer and it is an all-rounder when it comes to patient care and management.

# **CERTIFICATES & COURSES**

Course for Aspiring Hospital Directors National Health Institute, Kuala Lumpur	2018
Course on Research Paper Writing National Health Institute, Kuala Lumpur	2018
Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Workshop Faculty of Medicine, University Malaya	2015
Grief Response and Organ Donation Awareness (GRODA) National Transplant Center, Kuala Lumpur	2015
Basic Life Support (BLS) Basic & Difficult Airway Advanced Life Support Course	2015-2018
Writing and Publishing in Biomedical Research University Malaya	2012
Excellent Employee Award Hospital Sultan Ismail, Johor Bahru	2011
Obstetrics Anesthesia Symposium Hospital Sultan Ismail, Johor Bahru	2011
Intensive Care Workshop Hospital Segamat, Johor	2011
Antibiotic Workshop Hospital Sultan Ismail, Johor Bahru	2012
Cancer Pain Management Hospital Sultan Ismail, Johor Bahru	2013
Critical Care Updates on Current Practices In Intensive Care Hospital Sg. Buloh	2013
Annual Scientific Meeting on Intensive Care (ASMIC)	2013
Poster Presentation "Opioids And Post-Operative Ileus" Annual Scientific Meeting on Intensive Care (ASMIC)	2014
Jabatan Perkhidmatan Awam Malaysia (JPA) Scholarship For Overseas Medical Program	2001

## **ACTIVITIES**

Member of St. John's Ambulance Malaysia BLS, ACLS Examiner

Volunteer of Kechara Soup Kitchen Society, Malaysia Volunteering Medical Personnel

Member of Malaysian Medical Council Member of Malaysian Medical Association

Master of Ceremonies Anesthesia Day 2012, 2013, 2014 Hospital Sultan Ismail, JB

Master of Ceremonies Obstetrics Anesthesia Symposium 2016 Hospital Kuala Lumpur

Various Promotional Activities Awareness on Organ and Blood Donation 2013-2015

Contributor to The UNICEF Malaysia Contributor to The National Kidney Foundation Malaysia

CME Sessions with House Officers and Medical Students